Parker Phelps

Winston-Salem, NC 27103 | 336-8313432 | pp101socials@gmail.com

Summary

As a Front End Web Developer, I possess a wealth of experience and expertise in creating visually stunning and responsive user interfaces for websites and applications. With a deep understanding of web development technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, I have developed an extensive skill set in popular front-end frameworks such as React and Next.js.

Objective

Recent graduate with an Associate's Degree in Web Technologies and Programming and Software Development. Currently seeking to leverage skills in coding (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Next.js, ReactJS), problem-solving, and communication to gain professional experience in a Front-End Developer role.

Skills

- HTML5 (4 Years)
- CSS3 (4 Years)
- Responsive Design (4 Years)
- PowerPoint (4 Years)
- Word (4 Years)
- Excel (4 Years)
- ReactJS (3 Years)
- JavaScript (3 Years)
- SEO (2 Years)
- Bootstrap (2 Years)
- Sass/Scss (2 Years)
- Next.js (2 Years)
- PHP (2 Years)
- Git (2 Years)
- Scrum and Agile (2 Years)
- Java (2 Years)
- Photoshop (2 Years)
- Visual Basic (2 Years)

- Content Management System (CMS) (2 Years)
- .Net (2 Years)
- ASP.Net (2 Years)
- WordPress (2 Years)
- Adobe XD (2 Years)
- Python (2 Years)
- Swift (2 Years)
- UI/UX (2 Years)
- Illustrator (1 Year)
- Java Swing (1 Year)
- SQL (1 Year)
- Swing (1 Year)
- PyQt (1 Year)
- MongoDB (1 Year)
- SQLAlchemy (1 Year)
- Friendly, Positive Attitude
- Reliable and Trustworthy

Professional Experience

RTSYVISUALS | 11/2021 - 1/2022

Freelance Consultant - Lexington, NC

https://rtsyvisuals.com

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript and ReactJS
- Paid for professional experience
- Hosting images/videos onto personal hosting server to provide faster loading times
- Single-handedly design a fully responsive layout for the whole website

FIBERCOMPANY | 06/2023 - 06/2023

Freelance Consultant – Winston-Salem, NC

www.fibercompanync.com

- Single-handedly created with WIX and EditorX
- Paid for professional experience
- Hosting images/videos onto personal hosting server to provide faster loading times
- Single-handedly design a fully responsive layout for the whole website

RADIANCE GLOW HARDSURFACE CLEANING | 07/2023 - 08/2023

Freelance Consultant - Trinity, NC

https://www.radianceglowhsc.com

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript and ReactJS
- Paid for professional experience
- Hosting images/videos onto personal hosting server to provide faster loading times
- Single-handedly design a fully responsive layout for the whole website

ONLYJOJO | 03/2022 - 04/2022

Freelance Consultant - Winston Salem, NC

https://startling-syrniki-d0dc90.netlify.app/

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Made into an ecommerce-type website with a shopping cart system that uses Session and Local Storage
- Applied features that relate to the manga and anime of the same name through the website

A FRESH PLACE | 01/2022 - 02/2022

Freelance Consultant - Winston-Salem, NC

https://effulgent-marshmallow-23dfdf.netlify.app/

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and ReactJS
- Developed the site to work with Microsoft Edge, Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome
- Made with a shopping cart system similar to OnlyJojo's

SHARPQUILLS | 12/2021 - 01/2022

Freelance Consultant - Winston-Salem, NC

https://astounding-gaufre-f9428d.netlify.app/

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Created custom modals for displaying images of the different hedgehogs
- Used text and information based on each individual hedgehog type

FLORA AND FAUNA | 09/2022 - 09/2022

Freelance Consultant - Winston-Salem, NC

https://fantastic-starburst-b0f940.netlify.app/

- Created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Single-handedly created an informational site dedicated to all the native flora and fauna in NC
- Used text and information based on each individual specimen

Education and Training

Forsyth Technical Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Associate's

Programming and Software Development, 08/2020 – 05/2023

Forsyth Tech Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Associates

Web Technologies, 09/2018 - 05/2020

Forsyth Technical Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Certificate

IT - Web Technology - Web Fundamentals, 03/2019

CAPSTONE PROJECT | 03/2023 - 05/2023

Forsyth Tech Community College – Winston-Salem, NC

https://github.com/mxrked/Medical-Office-Administration

- Worked with team of programmers and database technicians.
- Created the login, navigation and scheduling appointments window.
- Linked backend to Local database.

Certifications

IT- Web Technology - Web Fundamentals March 2019

This certificate was gained when I was in Forsyth Tech Community College and took classes regarding the Web Fundamentals such as HTML5, CSS3.

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://codingthefront.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/parker-phelps-a121501b6/
- https://github.com/mxrked
- https://my.indeed.com/p/parkerp-lxyhsn9